Pedro Fernandes 1141 Broadview Avenue, M4K 2S6 Toronto, ON +1 416 505 2097 pedro92.gf@gmail.com

November 15, 2017

Tata Consultancy Services (TCS) Edmond, AB

Dear HR Manager:

Regarding the Software Developer entry level position, please find attached a copy of my resume for your consideration. I have extensive experience in software programming and design and I feel that my professional and educational background will satisfy the requirements of this position.

With a Bachelor's degree in Analysis and Software Development, Postgraduate degree in progress in Mobile Development, and hands-on experience using Java and .Net languages to create and implement software applications, I am confident I will be an asset to your organization.

Having worked within the industry for over 5 years, I have developed a wide range of skills that would meet, and exceed the expectations for the role. In my previous role as a Software Engineer at Samsung we have had many achievements, including published applications on Google Play Store and some directly delivered to the Samsung customers and, in my current role at Geolance I have the opportunity not just to work as a developer but also to manage other developers around the world which makes me understand a lot more about software projects and people roles.

I would relish the opportunity to bring this level of success to your company. If you would like to get in touch to discuss my application and to arrange an interview, I can be reached at anytime via my cell phone, +1 416 505 2097 or via email at pedro92.gf@gmail.com.

Thank you for your time and consideration. I look forward to hearing from you soon.

Sincerely,

Pedro Fernandes.

Pedro Fernandes

Toronto, ON • 04/20/1992 • +1 416 505 2097 • 1141 Broadview Avenue, M4K 2S6

Nationality Brazilian

E-mail pedro92.gf@gmail.com

Github https://github.com/pedrofg

LinkedIn https://www.linkedin.com/in/pedro-fernandes-a62a9431

SKILLS Programming

Java, Android, C#, ASP.NET, JavaScript, NodeJs, Angular, Html, Css.

Technologies, Libraries and Tools

Model View Controller, Model View Presenter, Object-oriented Programming, Aspect-oriented Programming, Material Design, Restful Web Services, JUnit, Mockito, Retrofit, RxAndroid, Flurry Api, JQuery, XML, Json, Ant, Gradle, Git, SVN, Gerrit, WordPress.

Static code Analysis

FindBugs, PMD, Lint, Protex.

Database Management System

SQL Server, MySQL.

EXPERIENCE

Software Engineer and Team Leader, Geolance (Canada)

Mar 2017 – Present

- Development of the Company's Website and Web Applications.
- Manage the Development Process working with Ukrainian team.
- Assist Customers and Sales Team in technical matters.
- Apply Code Review and work with Git Branches as part of the Process.
- Find Improvements and Gaps in Legacy code and Fix it.

Software Engineer, Samsung (Brazil)

Oct 2012 - May 2016

- Developing applications for Samsung smartphones and tablets based on Android OS.
- Developing Web Services and Web Applications.
- Creation and Maintenance of Unit Tests.

- Run static code analysis tools and fix bugs.
- Participation in requirements elicitation and projects planning.
- Maintenance of existing software.
- Work with agile methodology.
- Conduct code reviews.
- Involved in full product life cycle from design and development to deployment.
- Support trainee members, providing ongoing advice and guidance.

Trainee, Samsung (Brazil)

Feb 2012 – Oct 2012

- Developing applications for Samsung smartphones and tablets based on Android OS.
- Get code reviews from senior's engineers.
- Understanding user requirements.
- Provide improvements suggestions for software development.

EDUCATION

Mobile Application Design and Development

Lambton College, 2017 - 2019

Analysis and Software Development

Unibratec College, 2010 - 2013

.....

LANGUAGE

Portuguese: Native. English: Fluent.